Duryea, Perry B., Jr.; Papers apap084
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers
1961-1972
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Duryea, Perry B., Jr. (Perry Belmont), 1921-
apap084
2 cubic ft.
The Perry B Dunyea, Jr. papers is a collection documenting Dunyea's years as Republican Majority Leader of the State Assembly. This collection includes news clippings, a weekly column published about significant issues, Dunyea press releases, and other publicity materials released by his staff. This collection does not include any of his personal papers. The collection appears to be composed of material assembled for research about Duryea around 1972.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, before 2000.
Biographical Sketch
Perry B. Duryea, Jr. was born on October 18, 1921 in Montauk, New York. He married Elizabeth Ann (Weed) of Bronxville, New York and the couple raised their two children in Montauk where the family wholesale seafood business, Perry B. Duryea and Son, Inc., was located. Duryea graduated from East Hampton High School and earned his BA from Colgate University in 1942. He attained the rank of Lieutenant Commander in the U.S. Naval Air Transport Service and entered the family business full-time after World War II.
Duryea began his career in public service as a member of the Montauk Public School Board of Education. He was president of the Long Island State Park Commission, Bethpage Park Authority, Jones Beach State Parkway Authority from 1963 through 1969 and a member of the Board of Trustees of Colgate University and Dowling College. Duryea was first elected as a Republican to represent the First Assembly District of the New York Legislature in 1960. He served as Minority Leader in the Assembly from 1966 through 1968 and Majority Leader from 1968 through 1972.
Scope and Contents
The Perry B. Duryea, Jr. collection includes materials primarily documenting his years as Republican Majority Leader of the State Assembly. The bulk of the collection is composed of news clippings, press releases, and other publicity materials released by his staff. Some topics represented in the collection include state funding for care of the mentally ill through the state Department of Mental Hygiene, the New York State Kidney Institute, the future of higher education in New York State, the budget crises faced by New York City, and the state budget. Duryea's relationship with Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller is only covered in the news clippings file.
The collection best documents Duryea's coverage in the mass media through press releases, news clippings, and a weekly column he published about significant issues, but it does not include any of his personal papers. The collection appears to be composed of material assembled for research about Duryea around 1972..
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection has no series, and is ordered alphabetically.
Public Servants; Politics and Politicians; Legislative hearings--New York (State)--New York--1960-1970.; Legislative hearings--New York (State)--New York; New York (N.Y.). Department of Health and Mental Hygiene; Mentally ill--Care--New York (State); New York (State); Manuscripts; Press Releases; Newpaper column; Duryea, Perry B.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Office of the Majority Leader
- Assembly Chamber Welcome, Brochure, 1972 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 1)
- Assembly Memo, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 2)
- Biography, 1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 3)
- Campaign Literature, undated (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 4)
- Future of Higher Education in New York State, Conference, 1972 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 5)
- Legislative Activity, 1961-1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 6)
- Mental Health, 1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 7)
- Mental Health, 1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 8)
- New York State Kidney Disease Institute, 1967, 1972 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 9)
- News Clippings, 1968-1972 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 10)
- Photograph, circa 1970 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 11)
- Political Party Enrollment, 1966-1967, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 12)
- Press Releases, 1966, 1971/1972 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 13)
- State Budget Reductions, 1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 14)
- Weekly Columns, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (Perry B. Duryea Jr. Papers), Folder 15)